#哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hi everyone, I am Wang Gang
#最近在家里面又呆了十多天 十多天又过去了
Recently I have been staying home for more than 10 days
#然后今天给我四伯爷送几个口罩下去
Today I'm sending my uncle some face masks
#我买到了10个 给他送5个下去
I just bought 10 masks. Gonna give him 5
#十多天没出来 这个天气一天比一天好
Haven't been outside for a long time. The weather is getting better and better everyday
#我打电话听我四伯爷说菜籽花也开了
My uncle told me on the phone that the field mustard flowers are blooming
#今天回家乡看一下
I'm going back to my hometown to have a look today
#还有就是我们农村的那个关卡已经撤了
Also, the checkpost in my hometown has been removed
#也就是说可以回家了
That means I can go home
#但是回家的话还是要戴口罩
Although I still need to wear a mask when I visit
#所以就回去看看
Anyway, I'm going back
#好 走吧
Ok. Let's go!
#还有你们说我双手拿方向盘
And... some friends noticed that I hold the steering wheel with both hands
#我觉得开车的话就是要双手拿
Well, I believe that we should put both hands on the wheel while driving
#开车嘛 不能掉以轻心
You can't be too careful when driving
#更不能大意
Don't be negligent
#所以以后我成为老手了 也要双手拿方向盘
Even when I become an old hand in the future, I'll still hold it with two hands
#好了 现在我们要到村了 快到家了
Ok. Now we are arriving at the village. My home
#这个油菜花果然开得漫山遍野都是
Sure enough there are blooming rape flowers all over the hills
#十多天前呢 开得还不是很好
It was not like this more than ten days ago
#现在开得很漂亮
Now it's so beautiful
#去年的这个时候带着沺沺来看油菜花她开心的不得了
Last year Dian Dian was more than happy when I took her here to see the flowers
#等这次疫情过去了之后带两个小孩子出来看一下
When the epidemic is gone, I'm gonna bring my two kids here
#这个关卡也撤销了 可以回家了
This checkpost is cancelled. Now we can go home!
#真好
Great
#到家了
Now we are at home
#我四伯在那里洗菜还是干啥
My uncle seems to be washing vegetables over there
#现在我们农村这个喇叭天天都在放
Now the loudspeakers in the countryside keep broadcasting everyday
#如何预防这个新型冠状病毒
about how to prevent yourself from being infected by the coronavirus
#OK 到了 四伯爷
Ok. We're here, uncle!
#你在洗衣服呀 伯娘呢
You are doing the laundry. Where is my aunt?
#伯娘上厕所去了
Your aunt just went to the toilet
#哦 我给你拿了口罩来
Ok. I've got you some masks here
#只拿了5个
Only five
#你赶场的时候 你卖肉 去一回你就戴一个
When you sell pork at the market, remember to wear one at a time
#用了之后就丢了 这个是一次性的
Discard it after use. This is for single use
#要得
Alright
#一次性的啊
Single use?
#嗯 这个是一次性的
Yep. This is for single use
#要得
Ok!
#我看都好多人钓鱼哦
I saw a lot of people fishing
#钓鱼的人多得很
Yeah indeed
#大家都没走 就在家里呆着的
Nobody leaves their home (during the epidemic)
#（关卡）全部都撤了 街上全部都撤了
(The checkposts are) all cancelled. All the checkposts on the streets.
#撤了好撒 说明现在这个疫情就有好转撒
That's a good thing. It indicates that the situation is getting better
#说明这个疫情解放了撒
It means we are close to liberation!
#嗯 快解放了
Yes. We are close to liberation
#解放了就好了撒 那哈子老子遍游天下
That's great. I'm gonna travel around the world after this
#我从来没看都你洗过衣裳哦
I've never seen you doing the laundry
#你伯娘说她累都嘛
Your aunt complained that she was tired
#我是机器人 我又不累哦
I'm a robot. I don't feel tired
#累了我又加点油就是 就解决了
Just need some oil when I get tired
#吃点猪儿（猪肉）就是噶
You may need some pork?
#那不是咋子
Ain't that the truth
#我回来看哈这个油菜花
I came back to see the rape flowers
#可以按
Cool
#菜籽花啊 他们说现在都开完了都嘛很好看
Rape flowers. They said that now all the flowers are blooming
#没有开完
Not yet
#你没看见那边的马路好看得很
You didn't see. The road over there is amazingly beautiful
#是好看按 没开完
Sure. But not all flowers are blooming
#可能再等一个星期就开得完
Maybe... The peak will arrive in a week
#那会就更好看了噶
It'll be even more beautiful then
#对 那个时候看着就像遍地黄金
Yes. Like the earth is covered with gold
#遍地黄金按
Gold everywhere?
#不是咋子按 看都不是遍地黄金咋地
Definitely. Just like gold all over the ground
#这个（衣服）还清不清哦
Are you going to rinse (the clothes) again?
#看有泡泡没得嘛 有泡泡就再清一道
That depends on bubbles. I'll rinse it again if there are still bubbles.
#狗儿咯 来
Doggy. Come!
#你看嘛 它用脚爪来给你招手
See? He's waving his paw to say hello #这里狗全部用了he，不知道是否合适
#狗东西讨嫌得很
Annoying dog.
#干（吃）得 这么大的碗 一碗饭的话
He eats a lot. A bowl like this big, filled with rice
#拿起来 几下就吃了
He can finish it within seconds
#很有好重 狗东西跟秤砣一样
He's really heavy. The dog is like a weight
#它要跑啊 要整链子来套了 出来就到处跑
He's running away. You need to chain him up. He runs around once he gets out of the room
#这只狗是我朋友去年送给我的
My friend gave me this dog last year
#送来的时候以为养不活 现在这只狗可能都有7、8斤了
When he just arrived, we thought that he may not survive for a long time. Now he's about 3.5 ~ 4 kg in weight.
#是有7、8斤按
Exactly. 3.5 ~ 4 kg
#你看 它很迷茫
Look. He's confused
#是吗
Really?
#倒在这里面吗
Pour here?
#倒一半嘛
A half is ok
#好 差不多了
Ok. That's enough
#要得 四伯爷你慢慢洗哦
Fine. Enjoy your laundry then #请检查，感觉没有很好的翻译方法，容易变成命令的感觉
#要得啊
Alright
#我就不给你洗衣裳了
I'm not gonna do the laundry for you
#要得 你到处去游览哈嘛
Ok. Just go around and have a look
#嗯 我去看会儿油菜花
Yep. I'm going to see the rape flowers
#再过十来天等到这个菜花完全开了之后我们再来欣赏美景
We'll come here again to view the scene after 10 days or more, when all the flowers bloom
#好了本期视频到这里了
That's the end of this video
#拜拜
Bye-bye!